freedigitalphotos.net 2019-09-07

# Privacy policy - FreeDigitalPhotos.net

  * What we collect and what we do with it
  * Security
  * Cookies
  * Links to other websites
  * About us

This privacy policy sets out how FreeDigitalPhotos.net uses and protects any information that you give us when you use this website.

FreeDigitalPhotos.net is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

FreeDigitalPhotos.net may change this policy occasionally by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from 9 April 2016.

## What we collect and what we do with it

### Contact form

If you contact us using our contact form, we collect the following personal information:

  * Name
  * Email address

When you use our contact form we ask you whether you want to receive marketing emails from us. If you select 'Yes' we will occasionally send you emails relating to FreeDigitalPhotos.net, such as special offers and discounts, and about other services from us or associated companies. We will not pass your personal details on to any other company.

### Member registration

If you choose to register with FreeDigitalPhotos.net, we collect the following personal information:

  * Compulsory information: 
    * Email address
  * Optional information: 
    * Name
    * Business name and VAT number (if applicable)
    * Address
    * Telephone number

This information is used to enable you to sign in to FreeDigitalPhotos.net, access member-only features and make it easier to purchase images.

When you register we ask you whether you want to receive marketing emails from us. If you select 'Yes, you can contact me' we will occasionally send you emails relating to FreeDigitalPhotos.net, such as special offers and discounts, and about other services from us or associated companies. We will not pass your personal details on to any other company.

If you choose to register through your Facebook account, we collect the information available in your Facebook public profile and your email address.

We do not use this information for any purpose other than the management of your account, for example we do not post status updates on your behalf. We will not pass any of the information we obtain from Facebook on to any other company.

### Downloading images

We keep a record of all images downloaded from our website. If you download an image whilst logged in (whether free or paid for), this record is also available to you via your account.

#### Free downloads

If you download a free image whilst not logged in, we record the date of the download, together with the email address you gave and your IP address. This information is for administration purposes only.

#### Paid-for images

If you purchase an image whilst not logged in we keep a record of your name, address, email address and, if applicable, your business name. This information is used for administration purposes only.

### Contributor applications

If you apply to become a FreeDigitalPhotos.net Contributor we collect the following information:

  * Name
  * Email address
  * Telephone number
  * Address
  * Copy of photo identification

If you are accepted as a contributor we will also collect your PayPal email address (or an equivalent) in order to make payments to you. You will also have the option to specify what emails you do and don't wish to receive from us.

This information is required for us to prevent fraud in our application process and, if you are accepted, for the management of your account.

## Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

### Payment details

If you purchase images from us, we use trusted secure payment processors to take payment on our behalf. We do not store credit card details nor do we share customer details with any 3rd parties.

## Cookies

Like most websites, this one uses cookies. We use them to personalise content and ads, to provide social media features and to analyse our traffic. We also share information about your use of our site with our social media, advertising and analytics partners.

By continuing to use our website, you agree to accept cookies from us - our website will not operate properly without them.

The cookies we set broadly fall into these types:

### Personalisation cookies

These cookies enable you to log in to our website, and be "remembered" by us, which in turn enables you to use features such as your download history, the images saved in your lightboxes,  the contents of your shopping cart, and your currency preferences.

Because these cookies are essential to the correct operation of our website, we will always try and set them on your computer. You can prevent us from setting cookies by adjusting the privacy settings within your web browser, but bear in mind our website will not work properly if you do. Changing privacy settings in this way will then apply to all websites you visit, not just this one.

### Analytics cookies

We use Google Analytics to monitor how visitors move around the website and how they reached it. This is used so that we can see total (not individual) figures on which types of content users enjoy most, for example. This data is really important to us, as we use it to improve our service.  
[You can opt out of these cookies if you want](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

### Social media cookies

Some of our content is provided by social media companies. These companies might set a cookie on your computer when you view or interact with their content embedded in our website (for example, we have Facebook and Twitter feeds on our homepage).

You can view their privacy policies here:

### Advertising cookies

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and would like to know your options in relation to not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/).

## Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

## About us

FreeDigitalPhotos.net is operated by AgileBit Limited. If you would like any further information about how we collect and store your personal data, or if you wish to request a copy of the data we hold about you, please contact us.
